Hello everyone and
welcome to EnglishPod.
My name is Marco. My
name is Catherine and we're
shoe shopping again.
That's right we are going
shoe shopping but
this time it's a little
bit more complicated because
we're getting women's shoes.
That's right so there are so many
different kinds of women's shoes.
I'm not even sure I know
them all myself but in this
intermediate level
lesson we're going to
cover some of the
basics for you. That's right
so before we jump into this dialogue we
have a word that we want to preview with
you today and let's take a look at
it now on vocabulary preview. Very
vocabulary preview. Okay so we're shopping
today for a certain kind of shoe it's
not a sports shoe it's a dress shoe.
Okay that kind of doesn't make sense
because a dress is a noun. A shoe is a
noun and so you're want to get a shoe
that's a dress. No a dress shoe is a style
of shoe it means shoes that you wear when
you're wearing fancy clothes. So it's
kind of like a formal shoe a dress shoe is
for a shoe the type of shoe that would
go well with a dress. That's right not
sneakers but don't be fooled this is
not about dresses because men can wear
dress shoes too. That's right. It means
shoes you would wear to a conference or
to a wedding or to church. So these are
things that are a little bit fancier than
every day shoes. Okay awesome so we're
shopping for a dress shoe and there are
so many types and styles of shoes
for women so why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the first time
and we'll be back in a second.
Hi excuse me sir I'm looking for a
dress shoe my usual pair that I've had for
years have finally been stretched out
of shape they didn't provide any support
anymore. Sure what kind of shoe are
you looking for we've got strappy sandals
sleek high heels edgy pumps. If
you're looking for something a little more
practical we've got Mary Jane's ballerinas.
Show me some classic high heels please.
Okay right this way. What color
did you have in mind? Black classic.
Of course we've got this style here
that is very popular because it's an
open toe shoe you can wear any time
of the year. It looked great on everyone.
Um two shiny and I wear panty hoes
with my shoes so let's look for a closed
toe shoe. Okay these are a very nice
pair of leather shoes with a two-inch
heel so they are very comfortable.
I don't like the pointed toes.
Let me take a look at what else you
have to high that one looks like the
back would cut into my heel. I have a
high in-step so I doubt that one would fit
properly. I don't want bows.
I find slingbacks very uncomfortable.
Those might as well be
stilettos. Too modern. Oh finally
this is what I'm looking for.
With size. Seven and a half.
Here we are. How does it fit?
Mmm not good. They're too tight.
The length is right but the shoe is
too narrow and it's pinching my toes
and there'd be no room for my insels.
Oh you know what I don't think I have the
patience for this today. They just don't
make shoes like they used to. I'll come
back another time. Have a nice day.
All right we're back so a lot of shoe
styles as you notice a lot of them
are very I don't know I don't even know
what they are so I don't we try and
explain them now on language takeaway.
Language takeaway. So the first
kind of shoe we've got here is very
popular in the summer. It's called
a strappy sandal. A strappy sandal.
So we know what a sandal is.
Yeah it's a it's kind of like
what you wear to the beach.
It's a shoe that it doesn't really cover
your whole foot just the bottom. It's very
open and well what about strappy? Strappy
comes from the word strap so strap is
like a thin piece of fabric or
leather that connects other pieces
and so a strappy sandal means that it's
it's got many of these different little
straps on it. Many lines everywhere
that connect it so it's very open.
It's made of many different thin pieces.
Okay good so we have a strappy sandal
basically a sandal with many straps
and well she went on to describe
sleek high heels.
So this is a two-part thing here.
Sleek is an adjective which
basically means really cool looking.
Or more like it's it's
pretty and fancy and
usually sleek things
are also kind of simple
like a jaguar's very sleek
car. Okay and so this
is the adjective to
describe the high heels.
So we have high heels. Okay we have
high heels that are kind of fancy shoe.
Basically these are shoes that
are not flat so the heel is very tall.
That's right so basically this is what
a lot of women wear with dresses.
Basically the heel has a piece that kind of
sticks out and makes the women look taller.
So basically it's like they're walking
on the tips of their toes the entire time.
Right and they make click, click,
click, click. They make that sound.
But there are
different kinds of heels.
Okay high heels obviously
means that they're tall.
You can have low heels too
and those are shorter. Okay.
But high heels there are different kinds.
One kind is pumps.
Okay and the dialer we actually
saw the salesman describe them as
edgy pumps. So edgy what does edgy mean?
Edgy means cool. Core hip.
All right. So young
people like to wear edgy
clothes like rock and
roll kind of clothes.
Not so much older people.
Okay and pumps are a type
of high heel you say but
what is the difference?
Well pumps basically
are the kind of simple
heel that a woman will
wear with a pants suit
or with a skirt to the
office. And so they usually
have a closed toe and
they're quite simple heels.
Okay and the opposites
or maybe a little
bit different from
pumps would be stilettos.
So stilettos are a very
special kind of heel.
Stiletto. It refers
basically to the difference
in the back of the shoe
where you have the heel
because sometimes heels
are kind of thick and heavy
and they make the
clunk clunk sound. Right.
But stilettos are very,
very thin and very, very tall.
Okay. So stiletto heels.
I think it's probably
easier to walk with
pumps rather than stilettos.
Stilettos are famous for
being very, very hard to walk in.
It's almost like
the back of your
heel is a chopstick. Wow. I
cannot imagine doing that.
All right. So this
is the classification
of our high heels. Why don't
we move on now to marry jeans?
Okay. So we've got
high heels and heels.
We also have flats.
These are flat shoes.
So one important kind
of flat is a Mary Jane.
Sounds a good name.
Yeah, it is a name. Right.
Mary Jane. Mary Jane. So
what type of shoe is this?
This is basically a
usually leather shoe, but it
can be different materials.
And it's round in the
front and it has one strap and they're very
cute. Okay. Usually little girls wear Mary
jeans, but they're pretty popular these
days with older people too. Okay. Okay.
So they're round in the front.
They are usually black and
they have one little strap that
goes over the top of your foot.
Mary Jane. Okay. All right.
So we've taken a look at
Mary Jane's now moving on to,
I think it's a similar type
of shoe, ballerina shoes.
Well, ballerina shoes
are similar because
they're flat, but that's
about it. Ballerina shoes
are very, very thin.
They're very, very weak.
And usually they're
pretty simple.
They're pink or white or black.
And they're almost like a slipper.
Okay. So they don't
have the strap on top.
No, they're stretchy.
And you just lie
them onto your foot. It's
named after a dancer's,
ballerinas, you know,
the dancers who wear
pink and they put their
hair up and they spin around.
And they're not
hard on the bottom.
They're usually quite
soft and they're always flat.
So maybe these ballerina
shoes, they're not the specific
types of shoes for
dancing if you're a ballerina.
Right. But maybe
they're more adequate for
maybe walking around the
house or or something, you
don't really go out
hiking with ballerina shoes.
No, you don't go out
hiking, but they're very
popular to wear now
to school or work. Okay.
And the other type of shoes that we had
actually, this was really confusing to me,
a slingbacks, slingback
shoes. Well, slingbacks
can be hard because
they can be heels.
They could be pumps, but it basically refers
to a part of the shoe. So normal shoes,
they cover the back of
your foot, but slingbacks
have one strap in the back.
So maybe if I look at my
foot and a slingback, I
can see part of my heel.
Right. Okay. So slingbacks
have a little strap on
the back of your heel since the
shoe doesn't close in the back.
Right. Okay. But you also have a high
heels and women's shoes that don't close
in the back, but that
you don't have a strap in
the back either, right?
Those are open shoes.
So yeah, they're open in
the back, but the slingback,
there's one strap that
that keeps your shoe on.
Okay. A lot of different
types of shoes we've
just taken a look at. Why
don't we go back, listen
to the dialogue again
and we'll be back shortly
with Fluency Builder.
Hi, excuse me, sir.
I'm looking for a dress
shoe. My usual pair that I've
had for years have finally
been stretched out of shape.
They don't provide
any support anymore.
Sure. What kind of
shoe are you looking for?
We've got strappy sandals,
sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
If you're looking
for something a
little more practical, we've
got Mary Jane's, ballerinas.
Show me some classic
high heels, please.
Okay. Right this way. What
color did you have in mind?
Black classic. Of course.
We've got this style
here that is very popular.
Because it's an open toe
shoe, you can wear it any
time of the year. They
look great on everyone.
Two shiny. And I wear pantyhose with my
shoes. So let's look for a closed toe shoe.
Okay. These are a very
nice pair of leather shoes
with a two-inch heel. So
they are very comfortable.
I don't like the pointed toes.
Let me take a look at what else you have.
Too high. That one looks like
the back would cut into my heel.
I have a high in-step so I doubt that
one would fit properly. I don't want bows.
I find slingbacks very
uncomfortable. Those might as
well be stilettos. Too
modern. Oh, finally, this is
what I'm looking for.
What size? Seven and a half.
Here we are. How does
it fit? Mmm, not good.
They're too tight.
The length is right,
but the shoe is too narrow
and it's pinching my toes.
And there'd be no
room for my insoles.
You know what? I don't think I
have the patience for this today.
They just don't make shoes
like they used to. I'll come back
another time. Have a nice day. Ma'am.
All right. We're back. So now let's take a
look at five key things on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
Okay. Well, the reason
we're shopping today is
because the woman needs
a new pair of shoes because
her old shoes can't
be worn anymore.
What's wrong with the marker? She
said that they were stretched out of shape.
Okay. So to stretch or to be stretched
out, this means that maybe they've been
pulled and worn and
they're stretched so much
that they don't have the
original shape anymore.
Right. So just imagine
you have a new t-shirt
and all of a sudden somebody takes you from
your t-shirt and pulls you really hard.
And usually what happens
is this t-shirt is going to be
stretched out of shape.
You pulled it so hard that
it loses its original form.
So now maybe the neck
is very low or the t-shirt
is too long on one side.
Right. So that's what happens when you
stretch something out of shape. Great. Okay.
So her old shoes are stretched
out of shape and they don't
provide support anymore.
Okay. So to provide support.
Now what kind of
support is she referring to?
She's talking about foot
support. So for example,
slippers are kind of shoe basically that
don't provide support. They're very soft.
But can you walk around
all day and slippers? No.
It doesn't help your foot. But
if you're trying to find shoes
that are really good for
walking, you need to find
ones that provide support.
That means that always
support your foot, the
bottom of your foot.
Otherwise your
foot gets too tired.
Not only the bottom but it could
be also your ankle. For example,
if you can't really go hiking with shoes
like these with sandals because obviously
you're walking around
rocks and it doesn't
provide support on your ankle. Maybe you
can hurt your ankle if you don't have it.
So maybe a hiking boot will
provide more support. Exactly.
All right. And then the
woman also mentioned
that it's hard for her
to find a shoe because
she said, "I have a
high instep." Okay.
So think about the foot.
You've got toes in the very
front and a heel in the
very back. But in the middle
on top, you have the
instep. So this is basically
the top of your foot.
Okay. So if she has a high
instep, it means that
her foot is kind of thick.
That's right. Some
people have thin feet.
She has kind of a thick
foot. So fitting her foot into a
shoe is sometimes hard.
Right. We're not talking
about the width of the foot.
We're talking about the height.
Like the tall. How tall it is.
From the bottom to
the top of the foot. Right.
So that's what she means
by high instep. And well, they
also mentioned
different types of shoes.
She said she didn't
want an open toe shoe.
She wanted a closed toe shoe.
That's right. So this is a really
important classification for
women's shoes especially.
Open toe means that
the toe of the shoe,
the very, very front has
a hole or an opening.
So you can see the toes. Right.
A closed toe is the opposite.
So personally, in
the wintertime, I
always wear closed toe
shoes because I think open
toe shoes are too
cold. Too cold. Okay.
So that's basically, I guess
men, we don't really have this
type of shoe between
open toe and close toe.
No, maybe no, you don't
really. But heels, maybe you
could have an open toe.
You can have an open
toe shoe or close toe
shoe. Right. Right. Okay.
So a lot of interesting
things. This is useful
for women out there.
And also for boyfriends,
maybe now you know what type
of shoe your girlfriend may want.
That's right.
All right. So let's
listen to this dialogue
for the last time and
we'll be back shortly.
Hi, excuse me, sir.
I'm looking for a dress
shoe. My usual pair that
I've had for years have finally
been stretched out of shape.
They didn't provide
any support anymore.
Sure. What kind of
shoe are you looking for?
We've got strappy sandals,
sleek high heels, edgy pumps.
If you're looking for something
a little more practical, we've
got Mary Jane's ballerinas.
Show me some classic
high heels, please.
Okay. Right this way. What
color did you have in mind?
Black classic. Of
course, we've got this
style here that is very popular
because it's an open toe shoe.
You can wear it
any time of the year.
It looked great on
everyone. Um, too shiny.
And I wear panty hoes
with my shoes. So let's look
for a closed toe shoe.
Okay. These are a very
nice pair of leather
shoes with a two inch heel.
So they are very comfortable.
I don't like the pointed toes.
Let me take a look
at what else you have.
Too high. That one looks like
the back would cut into my heel.
I have a high in-step so I doubt
that one would fit properly. I don't want
bows. I find slingbacks very uncomfortable.
Those might as well
be stilettos. Too modern.
Oh, finally, this is
what I'm looking for.
Wood size. Seven
and a half. Here we are.
How does it fit? Mmm,
not good. They're too tight.
The length is right but the shoe is
too narrow and it's pinching my toes
and there'd be no
room for my insals.
Oh, you know what? I don't think
I have the patience for this today.
They just don't make shoes like they
used to. I'll come back another time.
Have a nice day. Ma'am.
All right, so
talking about shoes.
There's so many types and I
think women are notoriously
famous for having a
lot of shoes. Why is this?
Some women are. Some women
are. It depends on the person.
But part of the problem,
as you said earlier,
is that there's so many
different kinds of women
shoes that now we expect
women to have a different
pair of shoes for every
different occasion.
Mm-hmm. Work shoes,
hiking shoes, running
shoes, wedding shoes.
All right. I don't know.
Summer shoes,
winter shoes, fall shoes.
So you need so many
different kinds of shoes.
You end up buying many
different kinds. I think that that's
true and also basically
women like to look nice.
So that's why, you know,
you do your makeup,
you have earrings and
they have nice bags.
So I guess it's also
part of it is that you pay
more attention to what
type of shoe you're wearing
that maybe goes
well with the outfit.
I think maybe guys, not all guys,
obviously, as well as not all women.
But guys, they're a little bit more generic
as like jeans, pretty much go well with
any type of shoe as
long as it's maybe black
or brown, right, or
something like this.
True. Although I know a lot of guys
who have many different kinds of shoes.
True, true. It takes up a lot of
space in the cloud as well. It does.
It does. Shoes are hard to
carry around. And actually,
I find it kind of hard
to get rid of my shoes.
I think they have to be
ripped or just completely
unwearable in order for
me to throw a shoe away.
Because otherwise,
it's, you know, it's still,
you can still wear it
sometimes a weekend.
Yeah, that's true. Although I
tend to wear my shoes down.
That means I wear them
until they die. Really?
I'm sure they're the more.
I've had shoes that I've
worn the the the the
soles down and then I just
get it the sole change
because I like the shoe so much.
Well, let us know. Do
you guys like to buy shoes?
Do you have a lot of
shoes? Maybe you don't
have that many shoes?
We're curious to know about
this in other cultures
as well. Because I know
in the states, in the United
States, shoe shopping
is very, very popular.
And Holland, they have
traditional wooden
shoes. Yeah, they do.
Those are called clogs. Clogs.
So let us know maybe what
type of shoes are also very
unique to your country or culture.
We're at
EnglishPod.com. We'll see
everyone there. Bye. Bye.